thecollegeinvestor.com 2019-05-26

# Privacy Policy

The following privacy policy applies to the website administered by The College Investor, LLC (“The College Investor”), located at [https://thecollegeinvestor.com/](https://thecollegeinvestor.com/) (“Website”).  

Your use of the Website constitutes your acceptance of, and agreement to, the following Privacy Policy. The College Investor reserves the right to modify, alter, amend or update its Website, and Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is subject to change without notice. If you do not agree with or do not accept any part of this Privacy Policy, you must not use the Website.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED** **?**

  * **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website: The Website may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. **
  * **Information We Collect from Others: The Website may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for order fulfillment. **
  * **Automatically-Collected Information: The Website automatically collects certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, The Website will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. The Website may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.**
  * **Cookies: The Website may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. The Website may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.**

**HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

The Website may use the information collected in the following ways: 

  * To operate and maintain the Website; 
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings; 
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts; 
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries; 
  * To provide you with user support; 
  * To fulfill orders;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website; or,
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

**THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The Website may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information. Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers: 

  * Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. 
  * Drip – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. Drip stores your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. 
  * AdThrive and MyFinance – these services are used to manage our display advertisements. To provide personalized advertising options, AdThrive and MyFinance may track your IP address or location. This information is not stored on the Website. 
  * Influencer Networks – from time to time, as described herein, the Website may post sponsored content which contains tracking pixels for networks. These tracking pixels may capture information such as your IP address to evaluate the effectiveness of the marketing campaigns. This information is not stored on the Website. 
  * Teachable – this service is used to host the courses available on the Website.  The Website does not capture any data related to your purchase.
  * GumRoad – this service is used for the ebooks available on the Website.   The Website does not capture any data related to your purchase.
  * Simple Machine Forums – this service is used to support the forum found on the Website.  For the ability to post and comment, you may sign up for an account. To do so, you will need to provide your email address and choose a username and password.  The forum also captures your IP address.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion. 

Except when required by law, The College Investor  will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, The College Investor  may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

**PUBLICLY AVAILABLE INFORMATION**

The Website may include interactive sections such as commenting areas and the forum where you can post comments. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. If you create a user profile on the forum or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible.  To create a user profile, you must choose a username and password and input your email address for profile confirmation.  Your email address will never be available publicly. 

**ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, The College Investor may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies. 

**COOKIES**

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein. 

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests. The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history.  DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

**ADVERTISING**

**Display Ads** **  
** The Website uses AdThrive and MyFinance to manage all third-party advertising on the Website. AdThrive and MyFinance serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. AdThrive and MyFinance may collect IP addresses and location to serve personalized ads.  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**Retargeting Ads** **  
** From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, Reddit, Snapchat, Quora or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.   You may opt-out of this data collection by visiting the provider’s website and adjusting your privacy settings.

**Sponsored Content Tracking Pixels** **  
** This Website may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. As stated above, these pixels may capture your IP address on behalf of the content sponsor. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

**Affiliate Program Participation** **  
** The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.  

The College Investor, LLC is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

**Newsletters**  
On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, The College Investor may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows The College Investor to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

**RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**Opt-out** – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at robert (at) thecollegeinvestor.com to be removed from our mailing list. 

**Access** – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to robert (at) thecollegeinvestor.com. 

**Amend** – You may contact us at robert (at) thecollegeinvestor.com to amend or update your personal information. 

**Forget** – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to robert (at) thecollegeinvestor.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law. 

**SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy. 

**CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at robert@thecollegeinvestor.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

Last modified:  May 17, 2018
